当你看见飞碟来的时候 你最好祈祷吧
You'd better pray to the Lord When you see those flying saucers
世界末日就要来了
It may be the coming of the Judgment Day
嘿  杰利 你得来检查这个  帕洛马刚刚搜寻到
Hey, Jerry, you might wanna check this one out. Palomar just picked it up.
看起来像某些UFO类型正航向这里
Looks like some type of UFO, and it's heading this way.
告诉你多少次了
How many times do I have to tell you?
UFO不存在我们也决不会看到
UFOs don't exist and we're never gonna see...
-哇  它的能量讯号很大 -老天  该怎么办?
- Wow, its energy signature is massive. - Holy Cheez-Its! What do we do?!
没人告诉我们该怎么做
No one told us what to do!
我接这份工作的唯一理由是 可以什么都不用做
I took this job because you never have to do anything!
杰利  够了 我们来计算它的撞击点
Jerry, stop it. Let me calculate its impact point.
看起来像是
Looks like...
加州的莫德斯多
...Modesto, California.
超新星:这里是红矮星 我们确信发现到了
Supernova, this is Red Dwarf. We actually have one!
寇德.尼摩伊 复述  是寇德.尼摩伊
Code Nimoy! I repeat, Code Nimoy!
你们怎么都在这里? 才刚早上五点
What are you guys doing here? It's 5:00 in the morning.
快点  打开电视 快打开
Hurry, turn on the TV! Turn it on now!
..而稍早的晨雾消散后 将是晴空万里
...and some early morning fog, giving way to sunny skies.
华氏75度
Seventy-five degrees.
这是个好天气
A perfect day
可以驻足 展览会场欣赏老人家的园艺
to stop by the old folk art and craft show
或者向苏姗茉菲求婚
down at the fairgrounds, or a perfect day to marry Susan Murphy.
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, baby.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
还有早安  莫德斯多
And good morning, Modesto!
172频道
Channel 172.
你真是美丽  甜心
You look gorgeous, sweetheart.
谢谢  妈
Thanks, Mom.
啊  我的小女孩
My little girl!
爹地
Daddy!
我要你知道 尽管我要把你嫁出去了
Now, I want you to know that, even though I'm about to give you away...
但我会永远关心你
...I will always be here to take care of you.
别哭了  你哭我也会哭 会留下妆痕的
Don't cry because then you'll make me cry, and that's just gonna be a mess.
我管不住自己  哦 没法呀
I can't help it!
哈  各位  注意  注意
Hello, everyone! Attention, attention!
婚礼将在30分钟内开始
Wedding starts in 30 minutes!
-我美丽的媳妇 -嗨  荻朵妈妈
- My beautiful daughter-in-law! - Hi, Mama Dietl.
-就像童话故事 -气象员与气象员妻子
It's like a fairy tale. The Weatherman and the Weatherman's Wife.
-好浪漫
Romantic.
想想 明天这时候 我人就会在巴黎
I know. Just think, this time tomorrow, I'm gonna be in Paris!
我们不会只在那里渡蜜月 德瑞克会成为主播
And someday, we won't just be honeymooning there.
或者驻外记者 那时我们将环游世界
Derek will become an anchor or a foreign correspondent.
哦  甜心  我祝福你们
- And we'll travel all over the world. - Honey, my fingers are crossed.
姆指长短不一 是家族遗传
One thumb is shorter than the other. Runs in the family.
-德瑞克并没有啊 -是隔代遗传
Derek doesn't have that.
你的小孩会遗传到
It skips a generation. Your kids are gonna have it!
哇  你好漂亮
Wow, you look beautiful.
你也是..我是说  潇洒 我是说
So do you. I mean, handsome.
抱歉  我只是有些疲惫
I mean... Sorry. I'm just a little frazzled.
我只是花费太多时间 打发我们的父母
I just spent way too much time with our parents.
别担心  好吗? 很快就会清净了 只有我俩
Don't worry, OK? We'll be alone soon, just us.
嗯..在阳光下 品尝起司和法国长面包
Eating cheese and baguettes by the Seine,
互相喂食巧克力酱
feeding each other chocolate crepes.
-有问题吗? -没有  只是..
- Is something wrong? - No, no! It's just that, well...
计划有些稍微变更
There's been a slight change of plans.
我们不去巴黎了
We're not going to Paris.
什么? 怎不去了? 因为我们要去更好的地方
- What? Why not? - Because we're going somewhere better.
比巴黎更好? -哦  对呀! -哪呀?
- Better than Paris? - Oh, yeah.
-塔希提岛? -不对!
Where? Tahiti?!
福雷兹诺(位于加州)
Nope! Fresno!
福雷兹诺!
Fresno!
福雷兹诺?
Fresno.
福雷兹诺是在哪里? 会比巴黎更好  德瑞克?
In what universe is Fresno better than Paris, Derek?
就在..
In the "I've got an audition to become
我获得23频道晚间主播 面试的地方
Channel 23's new evening anchor" universe.
我刚接到 对方总经理的来电 要我去洽谈
Got the call from the general manager, he wants me to come in immediately!
很棒吧? 德瑞克
- Isn't that great? - Derek!
这太..
That's...
真吃惊
...amazing! It's amazing.
太好了 福雷兹诺是第五十大城对吧?
Fresno's a top 50 market, isn't it?
实际上是第五十五大城 但是我们就要实现了  宝贝
It's 55th, but we're on our way, babe!
想到巴黎..
Now, look. About Paris...
哦  没事..那很好 只要我们在一起
It's OK. It's fine! As long as we're together,
福雷兹诺就是世上 最浪漫的城市
Fresno is the most romantic city in the whole world.
-真为你骄傲 是为我俩.. -不仅是为我
- I'm so proud of you. - Of us! Not just of me.
是没错  但我们是一起的 你该为我们骄傲
I mean, of course, but we're a team now. You're so proud of us.
你该走了 看到我穿礼服会走楣运的
Now, get out of here. It's bad luck to see me in my dress.
哦  拜托  你知道 我不信那玩意儿的
Come on. You know I don't believe in that stuff.
我在教堂等你
I'll be waiting for you
我这英俊的新主播 也穿着礼服对吧?
at the altar... the handsome news anchor in the tux.
我爱你  好啦  我说了
Love you! There, I said it.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
苏姗!
Susan!
她人在哪呀?
Where could she be?
苏姗! 你在哪呀?
Susan! Where are you?!
苏姗  你跑去哪了?
Susan! Where have you been?!
我想我被陨石击中了
I think I just got hit by a meteorite.
哦  苏姗..新娘子在婚礼那天 都会有那种感觉
Oh, Susan. Every bride feels that way on her wedding day.
天呀! 看看你  全身脏的 还好我有湿毛巾
My goodness, look at you. You're filthy. Thank God I have Wet Ones.
你 光彩四射
You're glowing.
谢谢
Thank you.
不  苏姗  你好像 真的发光了  发绿光
No. No, Susan, you're, like, really glowing. You're green!
哦  不
Oh, no!
德瑞克
Derek!
不
Oh, my gosh!
怎么回事?
What's going on?!
发生什么事了? 你们都缩小了
- What's happening?! - You're all shrinking!
-不是的  是你变大了
Uh-uh! You're growing!
-那快阻止呀 给我接通政府
- Well, make it stop! - Get me the government!
这是不可能的
This is impossible!
不  这不该发生
No, this can't be happening.
等等  各位  没事的
Wait, wait. Everybody, it's OK!
享用点香槟 我们一起找出问题所在
Have some champagne while we're figuring this out!
姆指!姆指!
Thumbs! Thumbs!
德瑞克  帮我呀
Derek! Help me!
新娘子来了
Sweet Lord!
哦  卡尔 这是她的结婚日啊
- Here comes the bride! - Oh, Carl! It's her wedding day!
德瑞克!德瑞克!
Derek? Derek?
好痛  该死
Beam hurt Derek.
-苏珊  -你没事吧
- Susan? - Thank goodness you're OK!
我倒底怎么了?
What's happening to me?
别惊慌  别担心 无论如何  别掉了..
Don't panic! Don't worry! Whatever you do, don't drop...
德瑞克 抱歉  先生
- Derek! - Sorry, sir.
你们是谁呀? 你们在干什么呀?
Who are you people? What are you doing?
停手 小心!
Stop it! Be careful!
放开我  知道我是谁吗?
Get your hands off me! Don't you know who I am?!
拜托  离我远点
Please, just leave me alone!
行动  行动 快点  行动  行动
Move it, move it! Let's go! Move it, move it!
德瑞克!
Derek?
把那宝贝放到卡车上
All right, let's get this baby on the bus.
亲爱的  你能按下闹钟吗?
Honey, could you hit the snooze?
宝贝  为什么要设定钟响? 我们在渡蜜月耶
Baby, why did you set the alarm? We're on our honeymoon.
有人吗?
Hello?
怎么回事?
What's going on?
有人吗?
Hello?
安静  她会听到的
Silence, B.O.B.! She'll hear us!
有人吗?
Hello?
有人在那里吗?
Is there someone there?
能告诉我这是哪里吗?
Could you tell me where I am?
那是什么?
Hello? What was that?
你好
Hello.
快停下
Will you stop...?! Careful!
小心
Please, madam!
拜托  女士  停下
Stop! Doing! That!
无论是哪个疯子科学家 制造了你
Whatever mad scientist made you,
他都没戏唱了
he really went all out.
你能..说话
You can talk.
你好
Hi, there!
啊  我的背!
My back!
开玩笑的  我没有背
Just kidding! I don't have a back!
原谅他 如你所见  他没脑袋
Forgive him, but as you can see, he has no brain.
根本就不需要
Turns out you don't need one. Totally overrated!
完全吃太多了 事实上.. 我甚至不..
As a matter of fact, I don't even...
我忘记怎么呼吸了 我忘记怎么呼吸了
I forgot how to breathe! Don't know how to breathe!
帮帮我 卡克洛奇博士  拜托
Help me, Dr. Cockroach! Help!
吸气  鲍伯
Suck in, B.O.B.
谢谢  博士  你真是个救星
Thanks, Doc. You're a lifesaver.
哇  看看你 我知道你在想什么
Wow, look at you. I know what you're thinking.
在狱中第一天 你想在广场撂倒最强的家伙
First day in prison, you want to take down the toughest guy in the yard.
好  我倒想看你尝试..
Well, I'd like to see you try.
噢  她是沉默寡言的--- 她?
- Gosh. Look, she's speechless. - She?
是的  鲍伯 我们面前是个罕见的雌性怪兽
Yes, B.O.B.! We are in the presence of the rare female monster.
不可能！  是男孩吧 看他的胸
No way! It's a boy. Look at his boobies.
-我们得谈谈 -先生们
We need to have a talk. Gentlemen,
我们恐怕没给人好印象
I'm afraid we are not making a very good first impression.
-我们得谈谈 -多年来我们想要只新怪兽 像狼人
At least I'm talking. First new monster in years, we couldn't get a wolf man
或像木乃伊 总之就是能一起玩牌的
or a mummy? Just, you know, somebody to play cards with.
你叫什么名字  女士?
Might we ask your name, madam?
苏姗
Susan.
不  不  不  我们是说 你的怪兽名
No, no, no. We mean your monster name.
像人们见到你后 尖叫时的名字?
Like, what do people scream when they see you coming?
就像: "看啊!这里有个.."
You know, like, "Look out! Here comes...!"
苏姗
Susan.
真的吗?
Really?
苏~姗
Susan!
我刚吓到自己了 挺吓人的
I just scared myself. That is scary.
好耶!放饭时间
Yes! Eat times.
那真恶心
That is repulsive!
哦  我爱拖鞋
An old slipper!
哦  老天爷  拜托 告诉我这都不是真的
Oh, please, God, tell me this isn't real.
就告诉我 这只是面对婚礼的精神崩溃
Please tell me I had a nervous breakdown at the wedding, and now I'm
而我现就在心理医院 接受治疗
in a mental hospital on medication that's giving me hallucinations.
这一切都是幻觉
Don't scare Insectosaurus!
别吓坏虫怪索瑞斯
He's gonna pee himself,
他要是 自个撒尿  我们都会有麻烦
then we'll all be in trouble.
每个人都从门出来? 一定有个门才是  门在哪儿?
Every room has a door! There's gotta be a door here!
没事的  老兄 别担心
It's OK, buddy. Don't worry about it.
谁才是帅帅的虫子?
Who's a handsome bug, huh?
我搔你肚子时  你很享受吧?
You like it when I rub your tummy?
拜托  来个人啊 我不属于这里  让我出去
Please! Somebody! I don't belong here!
嘿  嘿  那可不是个好主意
- Let me out! - Hey, that is not a good idea.
让我出去
Let me out!
怪兽  回到你们的房间
Monsters, get back in your cells.
哦  感谢天 有个真人了 你是个真人  对吧?
Oh, thank goodness. A real person. You are a real person, right?
而不是半人半机器..你懂的?
Not one of those half-person, half-machine,
你们管那叫什么?
you know, whatever you call those things.
-生化人 -哦  不 你是个生化人?
- A cyborg? - Oh, no! You're a cyborg?!
女士  我向你保证 我不是生化人
Madam, I assure you, I am not a cyborg. The name is General W.R. Monger.
我是蒙格将军 我负责管理这个机构
I'm in charge of this facility. Now,
跟我来  该让你认识环境了
follow me. It is time for your orientation.
1950年
In 1950,
詹与乔决定 不让大众碰触怪兽的真相
it was decided that Jane and Joe Public could not handle the truth
而应该把焦点放在 像纳税那样更重要的事
about monsters, and should focus on more important things, like paying taxes.
因此政府说服人们相信 怪兽是神话与传奇里的东西
So the government convinced the world
并把怪兽关在这个机构
monsters were stuff of myth and legend and then locked them in this facility.
但我不是怪兽 我是个正常人
But I'm not a monster! I'm just a regular person.
我不会是个危害
I'm not a danger to anyone or anything.
别让她碰我
Don't let her get me!
抱歉
Sorry.
-我要在这里待多久? -无限期地
- How long will I be here? - Indefinitely.
-我能跟父母联络吗? -不行
- Can I contact my parents? - No.
-德瑞克? -也不行
- Derek? - Negative.
-他们知道我在哪吗? -不  他们决不会知道
- Do they know where I am? - No, and they never will!
这地方是机密档案
This place is an X file,
隐藏在隐蔽之中 掩盖在妄想的阴谋里头
wrapped in a cover-up and deep-fried in a paranoid conspiracy.
绝对无法与外界连系
There will be zero contact with the outside world.
7  8
...seven, eight...
我做了十轮了
I can't believe I did ten sets.
啊  苏姗
Susan!
希望铀元素不会用在你身上
You wouldn't happen to have any uranium on you?
只需要一点小污渍
I just need a smidge.
立刻取消卡克洛奇博士的 玩具盒特许
Rescind Dr. Cockroach's toy box privileges immediately.
我们让监狱的心理学家 重新装饰你的房间
We had the prison psychologist redecorate your cell.
试着让自己完全放轻松
Try to keep you all calm-like.
但我不要张海报
But I don't want a poster.
我要真的小猫 挂在真正的树上
I want a real kitten hanging from a real tree.
我想要回家
I want to go home.
哦  拜托  别哭了 你让我的关节炎又犯了
Come on, little Debbie, please don't cry. It makes my knees hurt.
别把这里当监狱
Don't think of this as a prison.
把这儿当旅馆你永远不能离开
Think of it as a hotel you never leave
因为这里从外面反锁了
because it's locked from the outside!
哦  还有件事
Oh, and one other thing.
政府改了你的名字叫 珍诺蜜卡
The government has changed your name to Ginormica.
开始重新激活程序
Begin reanimation sequence.
是谁胆敢吵醒我?
Who dares to wake me?
量子能已被探测出在一个 遥远的星球
Quantonium has been located on a distant planet
位在欧梅加象限
in the Omega Quadrant.
欧梅加象限? 解释
The Omega Quadrant? Lame.
量子流星的轨迹 标记在72-4区域
The trajectory of the Quantonium meteor has been traced to sector 72-4,
在当地称之为地球的星球
the planet locally known as Earth.
多可怜的一个泥球
What a miserable-looking mud ball.
派个机器人去探测
Send a robot probe!
不择手段取得量子能
Extract the Quantonium with extreme prejudice.
我要全部得到
I want it all.
每个最近掉落的
Every last drop!
是的  嘎勒煞
Yes, Gallaxhar.
没有任何事能阻挡我
Nothing can stand in my way now.
别冲动  凯蒂 我只是..还没准备好
Don't rush me, Katie! I'm just not ready.
哦  放轻松  卡伯特 就像跳舞一样
Relax, Cuthbert. It's just like dancing. I'll lead.
凯蒂 我明天有体育竞赛 也许我..
Katie, I have a gymnastics meet tomorrow. So maybe...
你打开顶棚了?
Did you open the top?
感谢老天  是警察
Thank goodness. It's the police.
我们什么都没干  长官 是呀  什么都没做
- We weren't doing anything, officer! - Yeah, nothing at all.
我怎么会让你说服来这里 也许我们该离开这里
Why did I even let you talk me into this?! Maybe we should get out of here.
也许我们该去查探看看 凯蒂  你疯了不成?
- Or, maybe, we should go check it out. - Katie, are you nuts?!
等等  别丢下我呀
Wait! Don't leave me alone!
我的脚踝
No! My ankle!
八成是断了
I think it's broken!
凯蒂
Katie?
这是我有过最糟糕的约会
This is the worst date ever.
凯蒂  我觉得怪怪的
Katie, I'm frightened.
它就在昨天午夜 被一对热拥中的男女发现
It was first spotted at midnight last night by a couple in romantic embrace.
没人知道它是什么 或打哪儿来
No one knows what it is or where it came from.
所有军事单位即刻展开行动
All branches of the military were immediately mobilized.
我刚接到讯息 美国总统已经到达
I have just received word that the president of the United States
将尝试做出首次接触
has arrived and will attempt to make first contact.
我必须独自接近它
I must approach it alone.
这全是有关和平交流
This is all about peaceful communication.
是的  总统先生
Yes, sir, Mr. President.
四周围已控制
Perimeter stable.
取得熊爸爸的 最佳视野  全部安全
Got a bead on Papa Bear. All clear.
指挥官  进行回击
Commander, do something violent!
-你们听到指令了 -开火回击
You heard the president! Light 'em up!
情况失控 请求空中支援  请求空中支援
We're getting pummeled here! Call in air support! Call in air support!
外星人回家去吧
请求..嗯  请求全面撤退
Call in... Call in a full retreat!
全面撤退  所有部队 全面撤退
Full retreat! Full retreat, all troops!
熊爸爸移动中 不  等等
- Wheels up. Papa Bear is on the move. - Wait.
这就是你要的吗? 吃子弹吧  外星人
So that's how you want to play it? Eat lead, alien robot!
-显然他们吃子弹 -把他拉进直升机
- Evidently, they eat lead. - Get him on the chopper.
我很勇敢 我是个勇敢的总统
I'm brave! I'm a brave president!
承认被认可的政府
- I say we invade it!
这个权利在这里也只剩两周时间
- The Earth only has two weeks left!
如果那东西走进人口稠密区 将会造成重大灾难
If that thing walks into a populated area there'll be a major catastrophe!
我们需要这方面顶尖的科学头脑 敢紧连系印度
We need our top scientific minds on this. Get India on the phone!
如果我们把美国人移往 更安全的星球..
Can we transport the United States to a safer planet?
我们该给那个外星人绿卡 让他骄傲做个美国人
Give this alien a green card and make him proud to be an American.
长官  每到像这种时刻
It's at dire times like this
我总会问自己:欧普拉会怎么做?
when I stop and ask myself, "What would Oprah do?"
得了吧 重点是什么? 这是个灾难
Hang it all! What's the point? It's a disaster.
-停下  长官 -别那么做  停下  不要
- Stop! No! - Don't do it!
那按钮是用来发射 所有核子弹
That button launches our nuclear missiles!
那么  哪个按钮能给我拿铁咖啡?
Well, which button gets me a latte?
呃..是另外一个  长官
That would be the other one, sir.
是哪个白痴设计的? 是你  长官
- What idiot designed this thing? - You did, sir.
够坦白 威尔森  开除某个人
- Fair enough. Wilson, fire somebody! - Yes, sir, Mr. President.
我不要以这种形式走入历史
Listen up. I'm not going to go down in history
一个在他的办公室眼睁睁
as the president who was in office
看着世界毁灭的总统
when the world came to an end,
所以大家敢紧想想办法
so somebody think of something, and think of it fast!
这卡布奇诺真不错 总统先生
- That is a good cup of joe. - Mr. President?
我不仅有个主意 还有个计划
Not only do I have an idea, but I have a plan!
常规武器用在那东西上 并没有效果
Now, conventional weapons have no effect on this thing,
而我们都知道 核武不是个好选择
- and we know nukes ain't an option. - Sure they are. I just...
-当然是好选择  按下.. -不  不  别按  等等
- Don't do it! Stop! - Wait!
我不是唬弄你  总统先生 前途暗淡 胜算并不大
I'm not gonna kid you, Mr. President. These are dark times.
我们需要圣母显灵
The odds are against us.
我们需要生力军  我们需要..
We need a Hail Mary pass. We need raw power! We need...
怪兽
...monsters.
怪兽!那当然了.. 太简单了
Monsters! Of course! It's so simple!
我..我没听懂你说的
I... I'm not following you.
这50年来 我掳获四处乱逛的怪兽
Over the last 50 years, I have captured monsters on the rampage,
把他们关押在一个秘密的监狱
and locked them up in a secret prison facility.
高度机密  所以连提及名字 都是犯了联邦罪
So secret that the mere mention of its name is a federal offense.
他不就正提到第50区..
Is he referring to Area Fifty...
总统先生 跟虫怪索瑞斯打声招呼吧
Mr. President, say hello to Insectosaurus!
蓉森小姐  拜托
Miss Ronson, please.
核子辐射将他从一只小虫
Nuclear radiation turned him from a small grub
变成一只350尺的巨大怪兽 导致东京遇袭
into a 350-foot-tall monster that attacked Tokyo.
而这个是 进化的失落环结
Here we have the Missing Link.
一个两万年前 被冰冻的老渔夫 被科学家们找到
A 20,000-year-old frozen fish man who was thawed out by scientists.
他逃脱了..继续在他的旧水域暴跳如雷
He escaped and went on a rampage in his old watering hole.
这个英俊的家伙是 卡克洛奇博士
This handsome fellow is Dr. Cockroach, Ph.D.,
是世上最出色的男人
the most brilliant man in the world.
他发明了个科学仪器 要让人类
He invented a scientific machine
拥有小强般的顽强生命力
that would give humans the cockroach's ability to survive.
很不幸这个是副作用
Unfortunately, there was a side effect.
接着  这东西叫鲍伯
Now, we call this thing B.O.B.
能来个人把她赶出去吗?
Will someone get her out of here?!
谢了
Thank you.
在一次以蕃茄做 生物遗传改变的化学实验中
A genetically altered tomato was combined with a chemically altered
打算将一般农作物变成 顶级的餐后点心
ranch-flavored dessert topping at a snack food plant.
实验产生的湿黏物获得知觉
The resulting goop gained consciousness,
变成无以破坏的胶团
and became an indestructible gelatinous mass.
我们最近新加入的是 珍诺蜜卡
And, our latest addition, Ginormica.
将军  继续
General, continue.
她整个身体辐射出纯能量
Her entire body radiates with pure energy,
导致她有着巨大的力量和体积
giving her enormous strength and size.
长官  这些是我们最好和唯一
Sir, these monsters are our best and only chance
有机会击败机器人的怪兽
to defeat that robot.
对付外星人就够烦了  将军
Don't we already have an alien problem, General?
我不希望再多个怪兽麻烦
I don't think we need a monster problem, too.
你有更好的主意不成  笨蛋?
You got a better idea, nerd?
好吧  请留步
OK. Stay where you are.
将军  我保证会进一步讨论
General, I propose we go forward
怪兽大战外星人的构想  谢谢
with your monsters-versus-aliens idea... thingy.
翻牌
Go fish.
三张的?
...threes?
是的  我有  你是怎么办到的?
Yes. I do! How are you doing this?
你是我见过最幸运的家伙了
- You're the luckiest guy I know.
这跟运气可没什么关系
- Luck ain't got nothin' to do with it.
搞什..?嘿!
What the...? Hey!
他们说我疯了 我会向他们证明 我会向他们证明
They called me crazy, but I'll show them. I'll show them all!
博士  我希望你不要像个 疯狂科学家那样发笑
Doctor, I'd prefer you didn't do your mad scientist laugh
我身上可挂了连结仪器的电线
while I'm hooked up to this machine.
你是对的  虫怪
You're right, Insecto.
你已在那个愚蠢实验上 耗时一个多月了
You've let that quack experiment on you for over a month.
我不是愚蠢 我是个疯狂科学家 那可不同
I'm not a quack! I'm a mad scientist! There is a difference.
大伙儿  我能有什么选择?
Guys, what choice do I have?
如果他能把我变正常 或少个几尺
If he can make me normal, or even six foot eight,
我就能离开这儿 回到原来的生活
I can get out of here, get back to the life
得到原本该有的幸福
I'm supposed to have.
-我是说  我应该.. -我猜是:福雷兹诺?
- I should be in... - Let me guess, Fresno?
福雷兹诺只是个中继站 下一站是:密尔瓦基
Well, Fresno is just a stepping stone. Next stop, Milwaukee.
然后是纽约 但愿终有一天..
- Then New York, then hopefully...
是啊  我们都知道:巴黎
- Yeah, we know. Paris.
启动开关吧  博士 但别再那样发笑了
Throw the switch, Doctor, but don't do the laugh.
现在你会感觉到脑袋有些疼痛
Now you're going to feel a slight pinch in the brain.
抱歉
Sorry.
苏姗!哟呼!
Susan!
我变小了吗?
Am I small again?
恐怕没有  亲爱的
I'm afraid not, my dear.
事实上 你还多长了几尺
In fact, you may actually have grown a couple of feet.
没关系  博士  我们明天再试试
That's OK, Doc. We'll try again tomorrow.
你真的没搞懂是吧? 从来没有怪兽能离开这里
You really don't get it, do you? No monster has ever gotten out of here!
那不是事实 隐形人就办到了
That's not true! The Invisible Man did.
不  他没有
No, he didn't. We just told you
我们这么说  是不要你心烦
that so you wouldn't get upset.
他25年前遭到致命攻击而死
He died of a heart attack 25 years ago.
不!
No!
是真的 就在那张椅子
Yeah... in that very chair.
他还在那儿?
He's still there.
明白了吗? 没人离开过  也不会有人离开
You see what I'm saying? Nobody's leaving. Nobody's ever getting out.
好消息  怪兽 你们要出去了
Good news, monsters! You're getting out!
除了今天
Until today.
那么我挑明着说  蒙格
So let me get this straight, Monger.
你要我们去打外星机器人
You want us to fight an alien robot.
美国总统已授权我批准你们获释
And, in exchange, the president of these United States
以做为交换条件
authorized me to grant you your freedom.
啊  真不敢相信
I can't believe it!
很快我就能回到 德瑞克的怀抱里
Soon, I'll be back in Derek's arms... ...or he'll be in mine.
我等不及要在春假 回到可可海滩  只要..
I can't wait for spring break back at Cocoa Beach, just
引发人群骚动
freaking everybody out.
而我将回到实验室 继续完成我的实验
And I'll go back to my lab and finally finish my experiments.
不  不  你说的是我  鲍伯
No! That's me, B.O.B.
那么  我会成为..真正的女巨人
- Then I'll be a really giant lady.
那说的是苏姗  鲍伯
- That's Susan, B.O.B.
好吧  那我会回到莫德斯多 跟德瑞克在一起
Fine. Then I'll go back to Modesto and be with Derek.
呃..那说的还是苏姗  鲍伯
That's still Susan, B.O.B.
我想至少该给我个 和德瑞克在一起的机会
I think I, at least, deserve a chance to be with Derek!
行了  走吧
All right, let's go!
大家要有秩序的移动 这是紧急事件
Everybody move in an orderly fashion! This is an emergency!
我们将撤离城市
We are evacuating the city!
这是正确的抉择  但也非必要的
Exact change is appreciated, but not necessary!
前进吧!
Let's move out!
这是旧金山 离我家并不远
This is San Francisco! This isn't far from my home!
感受风吹拂你的触须 是不是很棒啊?
Feel the wind on your antennae. Isn this wonderful?
我有50年没到外头了 真令人兴奋
I haven't been outside in 50 years. It's amazing out here!
好像比以前热了点 地球是不是变暖了
It's hotter than I remember. Has the Earth gotten warmer?
知道这回事真棒 实在是个好现象
That'd be great to know. That would be a very convenient truth.
那就是机器人 好巨大
- Now that's a robot! - It's huge.
别把它破坏的太严重
Try not to damage it too much.
我想将它带回机构
I might want to bring it back to the farm!
不  不  等等 你并没说它有那么巨大
No, no, no, wait! You didn't say anything about it being huge!
等等  别离开
Wait! No! Don't leave!
我想他在看我们
I think he sees us.
你好!嘿! 最近怎样?
Hello! Hi! How you doing?
欢迎  我们打算摧毁你
Welcome! We are here to destroy you!
我不能跟那东西打 我甚至不能.. 我..我在气喘
I can't fight that thing. I can't even... I've never...
有人有巨大的袋子吗?
I'm hyperventilating. Does anybody have a giant paper bag?
放轻松
Relax.
情势都在我老林克的控制下
Old Link's got this under control.
躲到城市里头  苏姗 你会没事的
Hide in the city, Susan. You'll be safe there.
但要躲开那大块头 他会让人有些昏眩
But stay away from the Tenderloin! It's a little dicey!
终于要行动了 我要把那个超大马口铁罐塞入..
Finally, some action. I'm gonna turn that oversized tin can
..真正的马口铁罐里头
into a really dented oversized tin can.
好吧  谁知道虫怪索瑞斯在哪?
OK! Does anybody have a 20 on Insectosaurus?
哇  瞧这大尺寸的东西!
Wow! Would you look at the size of that...
我抓到它了  大伙儿  我抓..
I got him, you guys! I got...
别担心  我不会放它走 我要穿下它..
Don't worry, I won't let go! I'm wearing him down!
他慢下来了
Please tell me he's slowing down!
到城市去  林克 我会尽快赶上你
Get to the city, Link. I'll catch up with you as soon as I can.
也许..你得赶上我才是
Or maybe you'll have to catch up with me.
不  不
Oh, no! No, no, no!
行了  行了  控制住了
OK, OK. I got this.
没错  很痛
Yep, that hurt.
赶到了  我有个计划
Get in! I have a plan!
热狗
Hot dogs!
好了  林克 我会靠上去阻挡它
All right, Link, I'm going to pull up alongside it!
你就准备进入 它的中央处理系统 然后..
You get up in there, get to its central processing unit, and...
嘿  大伙儿  抓住我!
- Hey, guys, catch me! - No!
快点  快点  保持移动
Let's go, let's go! Keep it moving!
嘿  不要鸣喇叭
Hey! No honking!
抱歉  移开点 在你右边..控制不了
Excuse me! Coming through! On your right! No control!
好的  会没事的 听着  我要救你出来 忍耐着点
OK! It's going to be OK! Look, I'm gonna get you out of there!
你得离开这座桥 不然..
Hold on a second! We have to get off the bridge before...
不  不  不! 离我远点!
No, no, no! Get away from me!
只是经过  没事
Coming through! Watch it!
嘿  毛球  你跑去哪了?
Hey, furball, where you been?
是啊  我知道 爸爸让情势有些走样
Yeah, I know. Papa's a little out of shape.
拜托  他要杀了我
Excuse me! He's trying to kill me!
他为什么要这样做  为什么..?
Why is it doing that? Why would it...
你干得不错! 我什么都肯干!
- Wow. You're doing great! - I'm doing everything!
撑不久  来吧  大伙儿 我们来搞定这东西
Not for long. Come on, you guys. Let's take this thing down!
是防护罩  挺典型的
A deflector shield. Typical.
你是压不扁小强的
You can't crush a cockroach!
虫怪索瑞斯
Insectosaurus!
-鲍伯! -什么?
- B.O.B.! - What?
帮帮我! 抱歉
- Help me! - Sorry.
我在盯着那边的鸟儿
- I was staring at this bird over there.
我们得把桥上的人疏散
- Get these people off the bridge!
得令
Got it.
不  鲍伯  把护栏移开
No, B.O.B.! Move the dividers!
哦  是  你说的对 我失误
Oh, yeah, you're right. My bad.
快  快  快  快
Go, go, go, go!
林克!
Link!
哦  好不舒服
Oh, I don't feel good.
行的  苏姗  你办得到的
OK. Susan, you can do this.
好吧  我们来搞定这东西
All right. Let's take this thing down.
搜寻任务失败
Retrieval has failed.
别烦恼  常有的事
Don't get upset. It happens to everyone.
那个低阶生命体 还以她能偷走我的量子能?
That lower life form thinks she can steal my Quantonium?!
再另外派只去探寻!
Send another probe at once!
量子能无法经由机器人取回
Quantonium cannot be retrieved via robot.
名为苏姗的碳基生命体 现在太强大了
Carbon-based life form, locally known as Susan, is now too strong.
哦  你认为你够大够壮..
Oh, you think because you're all big and strong
..可以破坏我的探测机器人
and you can destroy my robot probe
然后要我又躲又藏的
that you're gonna send me running and hiding?!
我躲躲藏藏的日子结束了
My days of running and hiding are over!
电脑 设定前往地球的航道 我要亲自取回量子能
Computer, set a course to Earth. I will retrieve the Quantonium myself,
纵使要把她的身体 撕裂成小细胞,也得干
even if I need to rip it out of her body one cell at a time!
小心点  很热的
Careful, it's hot.
三个星期前 你若叫我去打败
Three weeks ago, if you had asked me to defeat a giant alien robot,
巨形外星机器人 我肯定回答:办不到
I'd have said, "No can do."
但我办到了 你们看到我那时有多神勇吗?
But I did it! Me! I'm still buzzing. Did you see how strong I was?!
这世上不可能 有我打不开的瓶子
Probably isn't a jar in this world I can't open.
你真是我的英雄  亲爱的
You were positively heroic, my dear.
我最欣赏你 拯救桥上人群的举动
I especially loved how you saved those people on the bridge.
很令人感动 她挺让人惊讶对吧  林克?
It was a nice touch. Wasn't she amazing, Link?
对呀  很了起 很酷  我爱死了
Yeah, she was great. Really cool. Loved it.
可怜的林克  经过这般讨论后 你被个女孩比了下去
Oh, poor Link. After all that tough talk, you were out-monstered by a girl.
难怪你会沮丧 嘿  我不是沮丧 只是累了
- No wonder you're depressed. - Hey, I'm not depressed. I'm tired.
你怎么会累? 你什么也没干
Why are you tired? You didn't do anything.
我从没那么好睡过  好吗? 我得了睡猿症
Well, I haven't been sleeping well.
睡猿..困猿.. 随便啦  很不受
I got sleep apnes... apnea. Whatever. It's not fun.
那么林克有些荒疏 我是说睡觉误事
So Link's a little rusty... I mean, sleep deprived.
不久你会恢复原来的样子 我也一样
You'll be back to your old self in no time. And so will I.
那"世上没有我打不开的瓶子" 那股劲哪去了?
What happened to the "there isn't a jar in the world I can't open" stuff?
等等  你有找到打不开的瓶子? 里头是装什么?
Wait. Did you find a jar you couldn't open? Were pickles in it?
是泡菜吗? 装泡菜的瓶子在哪?
- Where's the giant jar of pickles?! - What my associate is trying to say
我想说这让我联想到
is that we all think the new
我想这个新苏姗 是只喵喵猫
Susan is the "cat's me-wow."
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢大伙儿 这么说很窝心
Thanks, you guys. That is so sweet,
但我有个正常生活要过 了解吧?
but I have a normal life waiting for me. You know?
明确告诉我
So, tell me,
你要如何以 这巨大身躯去过正常生活?
exactly, how this normal life thing works with you being giant.
我可不会永远都是巨人
I'm not gonna be a giant forever.
德瑞克不会放弃 直到找出方法治疗我的..
Derek won't rest until we've found a cure for my...
..病症 我们是团队
...condition. We're a team.
我们也帮得上忙 也许有天我们可以认识德瑞克
We could all do with a Derek. Perhaps, someday, we could make his acquaintance!
真的吗? 你们想见见德瑞克?
Really? You guys want to meet Derek?
第一站:莫德斯多
First stop, Modesto!
珍诺蜜卡  我通知你家人 说你快回家了
Ginormica, I called your family to let them know you were coming home.
也通知了莫德斯多警察单位 别对你开枪
Now, I also called the Modesto PD and told them not to shoot at you.
谢谢  将军
Thanks, General.
好的  要记得 人们不习惯看到..任何像..
OK, remember, these people aren't used to seeing... ...anything like...
你  或像你..或像你..
...you, or you... ...or you.
所以只要..冷静点 只要..知道吧?跟着我走
So just be, you know, cool. Just be... you know... Follow my lead.
停下  那是意外! 别破坏任何东西!
Stop! That was an accident! Don't destroy anything!
苏姗?
Susan?
苏姗? 妈?爹地?
- Susie Q! - Mom? Daddy?
他们有在你身上做实验吗? 没有  妈  我很好
- Did they experiment on you? - No, Mom. I'm fine.
没事的 他们跟着我来的
It's OK. They're with me.
他们是我的新朋友
These are my new friends.
哦  德瑞克  我好想念你
Oh, Derek! I missed you so much,
想想  我们重聚首了
thinking that we'd someday be together again!
希望我不会再回到监狱 我爱你  我爱这个男人
It's the only thing that got me through prison! I love you! I love this man!
不  鲍伯 那是我母亲 你会闷死她的
No, B.O.B.! That's my mother! You're suffocating her!
亲爱的  你没事吧?
Honey, are you all right?
我尝到火腿
- I taste ham.
抱歉  妈 他只是昏头昏脑的
- Sorry, Mom. He's just a hugger.
德瑞克在哪?
Where's Derek?
他在工作  甜心
He's at work, sweetie.
你也知道 他多在乎他的事业
You know how he is about his career.
没有德瑞克 就没必要庆祝了
- We're not gonna celebrate without him!
苏姗  我该拿你的朋友怎么办?
- Susan! What do I do with all your little friends?
请他们吃些小点心 他们什么都吃
Just put out some snacks! They'll eat anything!
哦  真是美味!
Ambrosia!
如何啊?
How's it going?
女朋友不错哦
Qu pasa, girlfriend?
开始狂欢了  虫怪
Way to cut up a rug, Insecto!
谁要跟林克一道游个泳啊?
Who wants to go for a swim with the Link?
嗨  我是 班左.维塔勒金.百卡布内
Hi. I'm Benzoate-Ostylezene-Bicarbonate.
你可以叫我鲍伯 这样叫容易些
Or you can call me "B.O.B.", whichever's easier.
我是不是太强硬了? 很抱歉  我有些粗俗
Did I come on too strong? I'm sorry.
我曾在狱中待了大半人生
I'm a little rusty. I've been in prison my whole life.
我为什么提到监狱?
Why'd I mention prison?
哦  我不是要吓你 我马上走开
I didn't mean to scare you. I'm just going to go.
啊  我觉得好蠢
I feel so stupid.
大家保持镇静 无论如何  不要激怒他们
All right, everyone, just stay calm. Whatever you do, do not provoke them.
大家要来点原子泡沫琴酒吗? 这种酒蛮..
Anyone care for an Atomic Gin Fizz? It's got quite a...
刺激的
...kick.
氯气  氯气 氯气进了我的眼睛
Chlorine! Chlorine in my eyes!
各位,逃生去吧
- They're turning on us!  - Everyone run for your lives!
他们要逃离什么?
What are they running away from?
..真是有趣  吉姆
That's hilarious, Jim.
那正是道地的乡下幽默
That's exactly the kind of down-home country humor
我在福雷兹诺时所会想念的
I'm gonna miss when I'm in Fresno.
这是德瑞克.狄托 播报的最后一次
This is Derek Dietl, signing off for the very last time.
晚安..莫德斯多 172频道
- Good night, Modesto! - Channel 172.
好..结束
And cut.
满意我的播报吗? 顺利完成
Did you like that sign off? Just made it up.
哦  我的老天
Oh, my goodness.
慢着  慢着  慢..
Wait, wait, wait! But, but...!
哦  德瑞克 你绝对无法想像 我这三周所发生的事
Oh, Derek. You wouldn't believe my last three weeks!
只有想着你 才能让我保持清醒
Thinking about you was the only thing that kept me sane.
不能呼吸
- Can't breathe! Ribs collapsing!
哦  糟糕  哦  糟糕 真是抱歉
- Oh, my gosh! I'm so sorry!
哦  天啊  好点了吗?
Oh, my goodness. Is that better?
好的  好的
OK. OK.
我还在适应我新的力道
I'm still kind of getting used to my new strength.
哇  你真的很大
Wow! You really are big!
是没错
Yeah,
但我还是我呀 我还是那个你所爱的女孩呀
but I'm still me. I'm still the same girl you fell in love with.
那个..毁坏金门大桥的女孩
Except you did just destroy the Golden Gate Bridge.
呃  那是阻止 巨形机器人的唯一方法
But that was the only way I could stop that giant robot!
你想过我能做像那样的事吗?
You ever think I could do something like that?
不  没有
No, I didn't. I can honestly say it never, ever, ever, ever,
我肯定的说 我从来..没想过那样的事
ever, ever, ever, ever, ever, ever, ever occurred to me.
我知道这有些不可思议
Look, I know this is a little weird.
好吧  是很不可思议 但我们会理出头绪的
OK, it's a lot weird, but we'll figure it out.
我们会一起找到方法 让我变回正常人
I know that, together, we can find a way to get me back to normal.
苏姗  请站在我的立场想想
Susan, try and look at this from my perspective.
我的新闻能左右观众
I have an audience that depends on me for news,
气象  运动  窝心的台词
weather, sports and heart-warming fluff pieces.
你却希望我把这些都放一旁
You expect me to put all that on hold
你就为你的遭遇 要毁掉这些?
while you try to undo this thing that happened to you?
那我就该全心全意配合?
That I had absolutely nothing to do with?
是啊 那确实是我所期盼的
Yes. That's exactly what I expect.
那我们所谈论关于未来的事呢? 你还想要吗?
What about the life we always talked about? Don't you still want that?
当然了  只是..
Of course. I just...
难道不明白 我怎么和你继续下去
...don't see how I can have that with you.
德瑞克  拜托.. 别这么做
Derek, please, don't do this.
你必须面对事实
You have to face facts, Susan.
别逼我这么说 我现在不打算结婚
Don't crush me for saying this, but I'm not looking to get married
并在别人的阴影下 渡过余生
and spend the rest of my life in someone else's shadow.
而你正投下相当大的阴影
And you're casting a pretty big shadow.
很抱歉 都结束了
I'm sorry. It's over.
祝你好运  苏姗
Good luck, Susan.
哇  多么喧嚣啊
Wow! What a shindig!
你父母的确知道 怎么控制场面
Your parents really know how to throw it down.
很棒的宴会
What? No, that was a great party,
是我出狱后  去过最好的之一
one of the best I've been to since I got out of prison.
我肯定是在不同的宴会
I must have been at a different party,
我倒觉得不怎么样
'cause that's not how I interpreted it at all.
我认为你父母不喜欢我
I don't think your parents liked me,
而且我认为 杰罗给我假的电话号码
and that JELL-O gave me a fake phone number.
至少垃圾是免费的 还有..
Well, at least the garbage was free. You know? I mean...
别自欺欺人了 即便我们拯救了
Ah, who are we kidding?
这星球上的每个城市
We could save every city on the planet,
他们还是会这样看待我们 他们本来就当我们是
and they'd still treat us the same way they've always treated us...
怪兽
...like monsters.
没错  怪兽们
Right. Monsters.
别提了 德瑞克的事呢?
Anyway, how is Derek?
德瑞克是个自私的蠢蛋
Derek is a selfish jerk.
-不是吧 -就是
- No! - Yes.
他许诺的未来
All that talk about "us." "I'm so proud of us."
我所憧憬的未来 只不过是他在福雷兹诺的工作
"Us just got a job in Fresno." There's no "us."
根本没有未来 只有德瑞克他自己
There was only Derek.
为什么我得被殒石击中 才看清事实?
Why did I have to get hit by a meteor to see that?
白痴!
I was such an idiot!
为什么我曾以为 和德瑞克厮守会很棒?
Why did I ever think life with Derek would be so great, anyway?
我是说 看看我所干的那些事
I mean, look at all the stuff I've done without him.
跟外星机器人战斗 那是我  可不是他
Fighting an alien robot? That was me, not him.
那太了不起了 遇上你们大伙儿 太了不起了
And that was amazing! Meeting you guys? Amazing.
卡克洛奇博士 你能爬上墙  还能..
Dr. Cockroach, you can crawl up walls
建造超级电脑
and build a supercomputer
只用到 一个披萨盒  二罐发胶  还有..
out of a pizza box, two cans of hairspray, and...
还有文件夹 了不起
- A paper clip! - Amazing!
而你  无须多做介绍 你正是进化的失落环结
And you! You hardly need an introduction. You're the Missing Link!
你曾在可可海滩 掳获250个女学生
You personally carried 250 co-eds off of Cocoa Beach,
仍有余力攻击国家警卫队
and still had strength to fight off the National Guard!
还有海岸警卫队 也有救生员
And the Coast Guard and, also, the lifeguard.
了不起
Amazing!
鲍伯  有谁能够从难以想像的
B.O.B.! Who else could fall
高度掉落却毫发无伤
from unimaginable heights and end up without a single scratch?
林克 是你
- Link? - You.
了不起
Amazing!
回应的好  虫怪 苏姗  不要欺骗自己
Good point, Insecto! Susan, don't short-change yourself!
哦  我不会再欺骗自己 绝对不会
Oh, I'm not going to short-change myself ever again!
苏姗
Susan!
加油!虫怪!
Way to go, Insecto!
虫怪  小心!
Insecto, look out!
虫怪索瑞斯!不..!
Insectosaurus! No!
不会有事的  看着我
You're gonna make it.
别阖上眼睛
It's going to be all right. Look at me.
千万别阖上眼睛
Don't you close those eyes. Don't you dare close those eyes.
不要..
You can't...
你一定很害怕
You must be terrified.
你在奇怪的地方醒来 穿着奇怪的衣服
You wake up in a strange place, wearing strange clothes,
被奇怪的生物囚禁 漂浮在奇怪的盘旋装置
imprisoned by a strange being floating on a strange hovering device.
很奇怪  是吧?
Strange, isn't it?
不会的 这不是第一次
Hardly. It's not the first time.
哇  你还真闲
Wow. You really get around.
你就在萃取室里头
To the extraction chamber!
听着  你想从我身上得到什么?
Look. What is it that you want from me?
你偷走确实属于我的东西
You have stolen what is rightfully mine!
我可没偷你什么东西
I didn't steal anything from you.
你巨怪的躯体 就包含有量子能
Your enormous, grotesque body contains Quantonium,
是世上最强力的物质
the most powerful substance in the universe.
你真的以为能占为己有吗?
Did you really think you could keep it from me?
就为了这个?
That's what this is all about?
你毁坏旧金山 使百万居民陷入恐惧
You destroyed San Francisco, you terrified millions of people...
还有杀了我朋友 就只为了得到这个?
...you killed my friend, just to get to me?
安静 你的声音在我的耳头嘎嘎作响
Silence! Your voice is grating on my ear nubs.
真可惜  量子能所能 展现的力量不是随处可见
It's a shame you won't be around to see what the power of Quantonium
某个有触角的人知道 该如何使用它
can do in the tentacles of someone who knows how to use it!
我知道该如何使用它
I know how to use it just fine!
别自寻烦恼 那力场是无法穿透..
Don't bother. That force field is impenetrab...
搞什么啊?
What the Flagnard?!
哈!那应该可以阻止你弱小..
That should stop your puny...
电脑  关闭第2舱门
Computer, close door, hangar two!
关闭第3舱门
Close door, hangar three!
关闭第4个
Door, hangar four!
全部关闭
Close them all!
电脑  开始粹取
Computer, begin extraction!
我终于可以在新的星球上 重建我的文明
Finally, I can rebuild my civilization on a new planet.
我该在哪里开张呢?
Any thoughts on where I should set up shop?
你的星球  行吧?
Your planet, perhaps?
你黏糊糊的触角 离我的星球远点
You keep your slimy tentacles off my planet!
你若想阻止我 当你有量子能时就该做了
If you wanted to stop me, you should have done it
现在你什么也不是
when you possessed the Quantonium!
下面的人们是无辜的 可没妨害过你呀
Now you're nothing.
在我的星球被摧毁前 那里的人们也是无辜的
There are innocent people down there who didn't do anything!
我很遗憾你的星球被摧毁
There were innocent people on my home planet before it was destroyed.
哦  不需要 我就是摧毁它的人 不解?
- I'm sorry your planet was destroyed. - Oh, don't be.
在我对你透露我的故事后
I'm the one who destroyed it. Confused?
所有的事都会变得清澈明朗
After I reveal my tale to you, everything will become crystal clear.
电脑..初始化无性繁殖机器
Computer, initialize cloning machine.
是的  嘎勒煞
Yes, Gallaxhar.
在很久以前 当我还只是只小乌贼
Many zentons ago, when I was but a squidling,
我发现到我父母是..
I found out my parents were...
没有孩子能够忍受那个的
No child should ever have to endure that!
所以我坚持己见 并与一只巨..
So I went on the road with a giant...
很快在那之后结婚了
And soon thereafter was married!
本来还过得不错 直到她想要..
Things were going well, until she wanted to...
那时我总回答:"不行"
And then I was all, "No way!",
而她总说:"行的"  于是我..
and she was all, "Yes, way," and I was like...
我想我对你说太多了
But I've told you too much already!
让我新诞生的星球命名为
Let the birth of my new planet, now called...
嘎勒煞星球  开始吧
..."Gallaxhar's Planet" begin!
UFO又再度降落美国
Once again, a UFO has landed in America,
似乎是UFO唯一想 降落的国家
the only country UFO's ever seem to land in.
抱歉..怎么回事? 好的  好的
Excuse me. What's that, Henshaw? Okey-dokey.
现在为您连线到 来自外星太空船的传送
We now take you, live, to a transmission from the alien spacecraft.
地球的人类 我为和平而来
Humans of Earth, I have come in peace.
你们不必怕我 对你们无害
You need not fear me. I mean you no harm.
然而  你们最该注意的是
However, it is important to note most of you
接着24小时内  你们将无法存活
will not survive the next 24 hours.
即便有人活下来 也将被奴役或拿来做实验
And those who do survive will be enslaved and experimented on.
你们对此不必有成见 仅是在做生意
You should in no way take any of this personally.
再扼要说明:
It's just business. So just to recap:
我为和平而来 对你们无害  但你们都得死
I come in peace, I mean you no harm and you all will die. Gallaxhar out.
传送完毕
OK, boys, set the terror level
好的  设定恐怖层级为棕色警戒 因为我得去换裤子
at code brown 'cause I need to change my pants.
我们该怎么做  博士?
- What're we gonna do now, Doc? - I...
不知道
I don't know.
我来告诉你们该怎么做 我们不该让虫怪白白送死
I'll tell you what we're gonna do. We're not gonna let Insecto die in vain.
我们要上去那里 找到苏姗  并且击败外星人
We're gonna get up there, find Susan, and we're gonna take that alien down!
好了先生们 你们的喷射背包
All right, you got enough juice in
有足够的燃料到达那里
those jetpacks to get up there,
但不够送你们回来
but not enough to make it home.
我会尽我所能来接你们 若办不到
I'll come get you if I can. If I don't,
表示我挂了 或来迟了
it means I'm dead. Or late.
我担任你们的监护人 将近50年了
I've been your warden for close to 50 years.
没比这更漫长的任务了
That's no longer the case.
但是这值得
For what it's worth...
那真无礼 我们做了什么呢?-不  鲍伯  那不是无礼
- That's rude. What did we do? - No, B.O.B., that's not rude.
那是表示尊敬的手势
That's a sign of respect.
将军  它正瞄准我们
General, it's targeting us!
就是这主意  中尉 保持这方向
That's the idea, Lieutenant. Hold your course.
全力右转  全力右转 全力右转
Hard right! Hard right!
控制不住 我控制不住
I can't shake it!
坚持到撞击 我们要狂飙一会儿
Hang on to your socks! We're going for a ride!
这就是为什么 我总是穿着降落伞  中尉
That's why I always wear a parachute, Lieutenant.
你可以放手了  中尉
You can let go of me now, Lieutenant.
-你这儿向谁打信号? -嘿  肃静
Who are you signaling? We're right here.
嘎勒煞万岁!
- Hail Gallaxhar!
不  不  不是全部 你  那个
- No, not all of you. You, there.
该怎么办? 另三个退后
How do I do this? Three back.
不  不  不  那位  就是你
No, no, no, no. That guy next to you. The one I'm pointing at!
就我指的那个
You! The one...
就是你..卡卡卡.. 就你  生化人  对  很好
You, clone! Yes! Good!
把人犯押解到焚化炉
Take the prisoner to the incinerator.
她对我们没有利用价值了
She's useless to us now.
-嘎勒煞万岁! -我万岁!
- Hail Gallaxhar. - Hail me.
珍诺蜜卡不再.. 像原来那样了
Wow. Ginormica ain't so... "ginormic" anymore.
我们该怎么救她呢? 他们人太多了
How are we supposed to get to her? There's too many of them.
办不到的
It's impossible.
我或许没脑袋  先生们 但我倒有个主意
I may not have a brain, gentlemen, but I have an idea.
这根本行不通
This is not going to work.
站住
Halt!
我.. 嘎勒煞命令你 即刻移交人犯
I... Gallaxhar, command you to hand over the prisoner this instant.
无疑地  你是无法 修理的瑕疵品
Clearly, you are defective beyond repair.
守卫  把这个瑕疵生化人 带去焚化炉
Guards, take this defective clone to the incinerator!
你们还在等什么? 你  还有你!
Well, what are you waiting for? You and you!
什么?真的?
Seriously?
是的  把人犯与瑕疵生化人带去焚化炉
Yes! Take the prisoner and the defective clone to the incinerator!
啊  当然  长官 这是安全通关卡 以备不需
- Of course, sir. - Here's a security pass, just in case.
-需要枝枪吗? -是的  需要
- Would you like a gun? - Yes, I would.
嘿  大伙儿  看呀
Hey, guys, look.
真不敢相信你们来救我 谢谢你们
I can't believe you guys came to save me. Thank you.
用不着客气 我们怪兽该相互依存
Don't mention it. We monsters got to stick together.
但我不再是怪兽了 我只是..我
But I'm not a monster anymore. I'm just me.
亲爱的  这无关你的尺寸 你永远..
My dear, no matter what your size, you'll always be...
什么也不是 只是个肮脏的碳基生命体
...nothing but a filthy, carbon-based life form!
嘎勒煞万岁!
Hail Gallaxhar!
Hail Gallaxhar.
这些伪装还真有效!
These disguises are the bomb!
就是了  跟我来
That's it! Follow me.
-有个方法能够拯救.. -嘎勒煞万岁!
- The only way to save the Earth... - Hail Gallaxhar!
嘎勒煞万岁!
Hail Gallaxhar. The only way...
-有个方法能够拯.. -嘎勒煞万岁!
- Hail Gallaxhar! - Hail Gallaxhar.
有个方法能够拯救地球 就是在入侵之前炸毁它
...to save the Earth is to blow up this ship...
嘎勒煞万岁!
- Hail Gallaxhar! - Hail Gallaxhar.
嘎勒煞万岁! 在入侵展开之前
- ...before the invasion starts.
-那么我们该怎么做?
- How are we gonna do this?
-我们得找到主动力核心
We need to find the main power core.
抱歉  你能指引 主动力核心在哪吗?
Excuse me, could you direct us to the main power core?
很乐意  就在那里 萃取室的上面
Gladly. It's right there, above the extraction chamber.
非常感谢 嘎勒煞万岁!
Thank you very much. Hail Gallaxhar.
-小心 -喔  当心点  笨蛋
- Watch out! - Look out, brainless!
给我那玩意儿
Give me that thing!
像这种武器 应该由负责任的人拿着
A weapon like this needs to be in the hands of someone responsible.
怎么?
What?!
嘎勒煞万岁?
Hail Gallaxhar?
-怪兽
Monsters!
-怪兽 怪兽?
- Monsters. - Monsters?!
注意! 所有外星人摧毁所有怪兽
Attention, all aliens! Destroy all monsters!
要试试这个吗?
You want some of this?!
你要伤害我朋友 就得过我这关
You want to hurt my friends, you'll have to go through me!
哦  对
Oh, yeah.
我们好像办到了
I can't believe we made it!
-天啊  -警告  发现侵入者
-O... M... G.  -Warning: Intruder
你绝无法破解 我的色彩密码
You'll never figure out my color code.
六音步的色彩密码系统 难以破解  但只消一会儿
A hexadecimal color code system. This won't be but a moment.
红  绿  蓝  黄  橘 宝贝蓝
Red, green, blue, yellow, orange, baby blue,
紫  粉红  棕  咖啡  梨色..
purple, pink, mauve, gold, brown, mocha, avocado, adobe gold!
博士  加油!跳吧!
Doc, come on, dance!
你失败累人的舞步 比不上我的安全设定
Your busted, tired dance moves are no match for my security protocols.
我们无法阻止他们太久
- We can't hold them off much longer!
有件事你并不知道  亲爱的
- One thing you don't know about me!
我的..博士学位..研究的是..
My Ph.D... is in...
跳舞
...dance! Dance! Dance!
安全设定被破解
Security protocol breached.
本舰已被设定为自毁
Ship has been set to self-destruct.
在T减6分钟后  全部摧毁
Total annihilation in T-minus six minutes.
-什么?马上发动入侵 -不再有能力入侵
- Well, launch the invasion then! - Invasion no longer possible.
电脑  将量子能导入舰桥
Oh, space balls! Divert the Quantonium to the bridge,
并准备好逃生舱
and prepare my escape capsule!
看哪!他们都吓跑了 怪兽赢了
Look at that! They're all running scared! Monsters win!
我不认为他们吓跑了
I don't think that's why they're running.
本舰将在T减5分钟后自毁
Ship will self-destruct in T-minus five minutes.
嘎勒煞万岁!
Hail Gallaxhar!
我们办不到
We're not gonna make it!
撑住
Hang on!
坚持住
Keep going!
没用的  难以撼动
It's no use. It won't budge.
我要还是珍诺蜜卡 就办得到了
If I was still Ginormica, I could do this!
苏姗  趁还有机会 快逃离这里吧
Get out of here while you still got the chance!
不  别这么说 我不会丢下你们的
No! Don't say that. I'm not leaving you guys.
你要的  找到蒙格
Yes, you are. Rendezvous with Monger.
他就在舰外面等你 去吧  趁还来得及
He's outside the ship, waiting for you. Go while there's still time.
本舰将在T减4分钟后自毁
Ship will self-destruct in T-minus four minutes.
别担心我们  苏姗
Don't you worry about us, Susan.
你终于有机会恢复原来的生活
You finally have a chance to get your old life back.
我不要我原来的生活
I don't want my old life back.
他们以为能阻止我?
They think they've stopped me?!
他们阻止不了
They've stopped nothing.
雌性碳基生命体 或称苏姗  不包含在内
Female carbon-based life form, or Susan, not contained.
什么?
What?!
探测机器人注意 攻击那个地球生物
Attention, robot probes! Crush the earthling!
机器人舱房已毁
Robot bay has been destroyed.
发射费佐伊火炮
Fire phasoid cannon!
你疯了吗? 你可能会杀了我!
Are you crazy?! You could have killed me!
那么我们彼此认识
Then we understand each other.
现在  打开门 放了我的朋友
Now, open the doors and let my friends go.
要不然呢?
Or what?
你该不会真的以为 你是我的对手吧?
You don't actually think you're a match for me, do you?
量子能已经成功导入舰桥
Quantonium has been successfully diverted to the bridge.
逃生舱  准备进行传送
Escape capsule ready for transport.
就像我之前所说 你该在拥有量子能时打败我
Like I told you before, you should have defeated me when you had the Quantonium
享受爆炸的乐趣
Have fun exploding!
现在  把门打开 即使我想  也办不到
- Now open the doors. - Even if I wanted to, I couldn't!
当你设定船舰自毁 就是这种情况了
That's what happens when you set a ship to self-destruct!
我们都死定了
Now we're all going to die!
而你无能为力 苏姗..
And there's nothing you can do about it, Susan!
我可不这么认为
I wouldn't be so sure.
还有  我叫珍诺蜜卡
And the name is Ginormica.
T减1分钟后毁灭
Total annihilation in T-minus one minute.
-很荣幸认识你  博士 -我也一样  朋友
- It's been an honor knowing you, Doc. - The feeling's mutual.
明天午餐再见  大伙儿
I'll see you guys tomorrow for lunch.
没错  鲍伯
That's right, B.O.B.
会有糖果  饼干  汽球
And there'll be candy and cake and balloons.
午餐有饼干和汽球?
Cake and balloons for lunch?!
那肯定是最棒的一天 我爱你们大伙儿
It's gonna be the best day ever! I love you guys!
救星来了
By Hawking's chair!
T减30秒后,全部毁灭
By Hawking's chair! Total annihilation in T-minus 30 seconds.
蒙格在哪呀? 他大概到这里了
- Where's Monger?! - He's supposed to be here!
他说他没到这里的唯一理由 就是他阵亡了
He said the only reason he wouldn't be here is if he was dead!
或来迟了
Or late!
虫怪索瑞斯  你还活着
Insectosaurus?! You're alive!
还变成蝴蝶了
And you're a... butterfly!
8,7,6,5,4
Eight... ...seven...six ...five... ...four...
-3  2  1 -拜托  拜托
- ...three... two... - Come on, come on!
哼  没事发生 也许我数..
Nothing happened. Maybe my count was...
哦  太好了
Oh, great.
哦  好家伙!
Oh, boy.
苏苏宝贝儿 -爹地
- Susie Q! - Daddy!
-哦  苏姗 在你还小的时候 我就知道有一天
Oh, Susan. Ever since you were a baby, I knew that someday...
你会拯救地球 免于外星人的入侵
...you would, you know, save the Earth from an invasion from outer space.
谢谢  但并不是只有我  妈
Thank you, but it wasn't just me, Mom.
抱歉  借过  你好吗?
Excuse me! Hello! Coming through! How are you?
苏姗! 德瑞克?
- Susan! - Derek?
宝贝  我反覆思索 我们之间发生的事
Baby, I thought long and hard about what happened between us.
我要你知道  我原谅你
And I want you to know... ...I forgive you.
你原谅我?
You forgive me?
当然了  这并不是你的错 你被殒石击中才破坏了所有的事
Of course. It wasn't your fault you got hit by a meteor and ruined everything.
你知道吗?
And you know what?
我想也许你没破坏所有的事
I say maybe you didn't ruin everything.
我刚接到纽约的来电 他们提议我到无线台
I just got a call from New York. They offered me network.
只要我能取得 你的独家采访
All I have to do is get an exclusive interview from you.
真的?
Really?
对呀  我得梦想的工作 而你得到梦想的男人
Yeah. I get my dream job and you get your dream guy.
这是狄托团队的双赢
It's a win-win for Team Dietl.
德瑞克  那太棒了
Derek... ...that's amazing.
- 摄影机是开着的吗? - 确实是..
- Is the camera rolling? - Absolutely.
很好  我不希望你的影迷 错过这个镜头
Good. Because I wouldn't want your fans to miss this.
这是苏姗茉菲说..
This is Susan Murphy, saying,
再见..德瑞克!
"Goodbye, Derek!"
鲍伯  你能呃..?
B.O.B., could you...?
德瑞克  你是个自私的混蛋 猜怎么着?
Derek, you are a selfish jerk, and guess what?
我爱上别的人了 她是柠檬绿
I've met someone else. She's lime green.
她内含14小块凤梨果肉
She has 14 little chunks of pineapple inside her,
她是我生命中最应得的
and she's everything I deserve in life!
我很快乐  德瑞克  不需要你  都结束了
I'm happy now, Derek, without you! It's over!
关机吧
Turn it off.
怪兽们  我为你们骄傲得想哭
Monsters, I'm so proud of you, I could cry,
要是我没战争中失去眼泪的话
if I hadn't lost my tear ducts in the war.
没时间哭哭啼啼 这世界又需要你们了
But not crying will have to wait. The world needs you again.
怎么回事  将军?
What is it, General?
好像有只蜗牛掉入 法国的核子反应炉
Seems a snail fell into a French nuclear reactor.
我们说话的同时
As we speak, Escargantua
蜗牛怪正慢慢移往巴黎
is slowly making its way to Paris.
我一直都想去巴黎  现在  谁要跟我去?
Well, I've always wanted to go to Paris. Now who's with me?
你怎么说? 蝴蝶索瑞斯?
What do you say, Butterfly... osaurus?
我们加入
We're in.
-我加入 -也把我算进去
- I'm in! - Count me in, too.
再见  甜心
Au revoir, sweetie!
-一路顺风 -对呀  还有要抓牢
- Have a safe flight! - Yeah, and hang on!
再见  德瑞克 最好忘掉我吧
Goodbye, Derek! Good luck getting over me.
鲍伯  我才是 不过他绝对忘不掉的
B.O.B., it's me he's never going to get over.
等等 你也曾和德瑞克交往过?
Wait, wait! You were dating Derek too?!
那混蛋脚踏两只船!
That two-timing jerk!
各位  让我们欢迎新任的 参谋长联席会议主席
Everyone, let's welcome my new chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff,
W.R.蒙格将军
General W.R. Monger!
谢谢  总统先生 以这种方式庆祝
Thank you, Mr. President.
联席会议成立九十周年  很不错
What a great way to celebrate my 90th birthday.
非常好  沃伦
Very good, Warren. All right.
好了  那我们就开始吧
Let's get it started in here Nerd?
蠢蛋  先生们  我要发一份 初步预算报告
Gentlemen, I have assembled a preliminary budget estimate
是关于旧金山的重建工作
for the rebuilding of San Francisco.
看起来挺无聊的
Zoinkers. This is going to be a boring one.
是喝杯咖啡的好时候  沃伦  要来点什么?
Good time for a cup of joe. Warren, how do you take it?
给我经典法式巧克力甜饼 还要有机法布奇诺咖啡
Hit me with a double venti organic chocolate brownie
要热的  而且还要是..
caramel Frappuccino, extra hot, with one inch of foam...
-无脂肪 -如你所愿
- ...non-fat. - You got it! Black it is.
别那样
Don't do it!
马上来
Wait!
天啊!老兄!你做了什么?
My God, man! What have you done?!
该是举白旗 并躲进掩体的时候了  孩子们
Time to wave the white flag and head for the bunker.
我们五百年后 再来检验这情势
Let's check on the situation in 500 years.
有谁要冷冻我的脑袋?
Who wants to freeze my head?